Guide to the Ithaca Feminist Radio Collective, "Being Ourselves" records, 1970-1998
Ithaca Feminist Radio Collection, "Being Ourselves" records, 1970-1998
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ithaca Feminist Radio Collective, "Being Ourselves" records, 1970-1998
6483
Ithaca Feminist Radio Collective
33.2 cubic ft.
Audiotapes, studio and meeting notes, correspondence, articles.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Audiotapes of "Being Ourselves," a program that was produced by the Ithaca Feminist Radio Collective and broadcast in Ithaca, NY, on Sunday mornings. Also, notes and files from collective meetings and relating to producing the show.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Collective members changed over the years. An incomplete list of members includes: Leni Hochman, Judy Scherer, Jennifer Greene, Sara Shenk, Robin Whittlesey, Miriam Graham, Patrice Jennings, Deb Whiter, and Wendy Kohli. Designed to address a broad spectrum of women's issues, the show aired interviews with local and visiting activists, writers, artists, and thinkers, as well as women's music.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Audiotapes of "Being Ourselves," a program that was produced by the Ithaca Feminist Radio Collective and broadcast in Ithaca, NY, on Sunday mornings. Also, notes and files from collective meetings and relating to producing the show.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The IFRC collection consists of six series, arranged with print material first, then the audio material, and lastly miscellany: I. General, II. Funding, III. Program Planning, IV. Printed Material, V. "Being Ourselves" Audiotapes, and VI. Miscellaneous
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ithaca Feminist Radio Collective
Titles:
Being Ourselves (Ithaca, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Feminism and music; Feminists; Radio and women; Radio programs--Ithaca (N.Y.); Women's music
Form and Genre Terms:
Audio tapes
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. General
Box 1
Series II. Funding
Boxes 1-2
Series III. Program Planning
Boxes 1-5
Series IV. Printed Materials
Boxes 3, 6-7
Series V. "Being Ourselves" Audiotapes
Boxes 8-38
Series VI. Miscellaneous
Box 6
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General
  - Statement of purpose, 1986, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Forms and certificates, 1988-1995, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - IFRC members, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address cards, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. Funding
  - Funding information, 1981-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alternatives Fund, 1983-1985, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arts Council of Tompkins County, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Resist, 1987-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chemung Valley Arts Council, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Pyramid Mall, Ithaca, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Community Arts Partnership, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget and Administration Community, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series III. Program Planning
  - Correspondence, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1996, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting notes, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting notes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting notes, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting notes, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting notes, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting notes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting notes, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Music reviews, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Recruitment and list of shows, 1981-1996, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Feedback, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Program log, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Training manual, 1977-1978, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Studio notes (not in order), 1976-1992, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Studio notes, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Studio notes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Studio notes, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Studio notes: General (not in order), 1979-1981, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Studio notes: General (not in order), 1979-1982, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Studio notes: General (not in order), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Studio notes: General (not in order), 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Studio notes, 1981, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Studio notes, 1982-1983, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Studio notes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Studio notes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Studio notes, 1984, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Studio notes, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Studio notes, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Studio notes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Studio notes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Studio notes, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Studio notes, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Studio notes, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Studio notes, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Studio notes, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Studio notes (not in order), 1991-1992, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Studio notes, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Studio notes, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Studio notes, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Studio notes, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Studio notes: General (not in order), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Studio notes, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Studio notes, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series IV. Printed Material
  - Articles and IFR Publicity, 1961-1996, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Directories, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Brochures and flyers, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Publications, 1972-1994, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ladyslipper catalogs, 1984-1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers, 1981-1998, n.d. (Box 7)
- Series V. "Being Ourselves" Audiotapes
  - Large reels, 1970-1976 (Box 8)
  - Large reels, 1970-1977, n.d. (Box 9)
  - Large reels, 1970-1978, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Large reels, 1970-1979, n.d. (Box 11)
  - 7" reels: Shows 1-23, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Various reel sizes, 1975-1977 (Box 13)
  - Large reels, 1975-1978, n.d. (Box 14)
  - Large reels, 1975-1980, n.d. (Box 15)
  - 5" reels, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
  - 5" & 7" reels, 1976-1977 (Box 17)
  - Small reels, 1978-1981 (Box 18)
  - Small reels, 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - 7" reels, 1982-1983, n.d. (Box 20)
  - 7" reels, 1983, n.d. (Box 21)
  - 7" reels, 1984 (Box 22)
  - 7" reels, 1984-1985 (Box 23)
  - 7" reels, 1985-1986 (Box 24)
  - 7" reels, 1986-1987 (Box 25)
  - 7" reels, 1987-1988 (Box 26)
  - 7" reels, 1988 (Box 27)
  - 7" reels, 1988-1989 (Box 28)
  - 7" reels, 1989-1990 (Box 29)
  - 7" reels, 1990-1991 (Box 30)
  - 7" reels, 1991-1992 (Box 31)
  - 7" reels, 1992-1993 (Box 32)
  - 7" reels, 1993-1994 (Box 33)
  - 7" reels, 1994 (Box 34)
  - 7" reels, 1995-1996 (Box 35)
  - 7" reels, 1996-1997 (Box 36)
  - 7" reels, 1997 (Box 37)
  - 7" reels, 1998 (Box 38)
  - Unidentified reels, n.d. (Box 39)
  - Digital copies of selected reels, 1970s; CD-1860-1889 (Box 40)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous
  - Poems and Stories: Writing Workshop, 1993, 1993; DVD-151 (Box 2)
  - Tape labels, 1985-1996, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Invoices and check books, 1978-1997, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Contact sheet of photograph taken for March 26, 1987 Ithaca Times story, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)